# **OGUNDERO MICHEAL AYODEJI**

+2348087365099 | ogunderoayodeji@gmail.com | Mushin, Lagos, Nigeria

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Experienced and top-performing IT professional with over 6 years of experience in full stack software engineering, development, programming, quality assurance, support and implementation in the ecommerce and fintech industries. Designing and developing intuitive full-stack enterprise web applications with contribution to software architecture design, requirements gathering, technical specification, applying solid design principles and software design patterns across multiple technology stacks and promoting software engineering best practices. Deep programming language knowledge with working knowledge of the general mobile landscape, architectures, trends, and emerging technologies; solid understanding of the full mobile development life cycle; critical thinker and problem-solving skills.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Web & Software
  Development
- Programming Languages
- SDLC Project Delivery
- Applications Architecture
- User Requirements

- IT Risk Assessment
- Quality Assurance
- System Migration & Integration
- Technical Architecture Design
- System Integration & Testing
- Access Management
- Data Interpretation
- Instrumentation & Control Systems

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Software Engineer - Syarpa., UK / Nigeria

Jan. 2022 - Present

- Participates in technical specification and software architecture design
- Documents and demonstrates solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments and clear code.
- Designs and updates software using collected data, systems analysis and prior bug reports.
- Confers with management teams regarding user reports to personalize software and increase productivity.
- Handles payments processes (both crypto and fiat) on the platform.
- Builds the microservice to manually manage exchange rates on the website with NodeJS/NestJS framework.

# **Software Engineer -** The Bulb Africa

May. 2021 – Dec. 2021

- Worked with project & product managers, QA Engineers to own solution from development to production
- Implemented signalR and Redis to effectively handle real-time communication between the backend-service and the mobile app.
- Handled bill payments, airtime and data recharge integrations with different service providers.
- Developed the settl.me USSD application that allows users to create account, pay bills, buy airtime, request money, transfer money and perform some other functions via a USSD channel.
- Tracked, documented, and maintained software and network system functionality—both internally and externally, leveraging opportunities to improve engineering productivity.
- Engaged in software testing to identify defects early in the development process and ensure quality assurance.

### **Contract Software Engineer -** Syarpa., UK / Nigeria

Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Developed key components to support identity, authentication, and mobile engagement features.
- Managed and spearheaded all OTP requests and validation processes for login, transactions and two-FA.
- Worked with Coinbase API and AbokiFx API to fetch current exchange rates and also integrated Stripe and Circle APIs to handle payout to customers.
- Involved in the authentication, identification and documentation of verification processes and implemented integrations with Flutterwave & Loquet for Nigeria and UK accounts validation respectively.

## Contract Software Engineer - Polaris Bank Ltd

Dec. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- Refactored some processes between Polaris bank and NIBBS for inward and outward transfers to the bank.
- Assessed customer and internal project requirements to execute new accessories and modify all existing solutions.
- Maintained knowledge of technologies which cover API specification, Financial Information Exchange and latest developments.
- Ensured optimal knowledge on all bank trading process and ensure speedy development and reliable service and acceleration of product quality.

# **Software Engineering Consultant –** "Cervitech" Mobile Application

Apr. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Participated in the complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) for development, testing, and code enhancement.
- Wrote technical specifications and maintained all reports about application development processes.
- Implemented FCM push notification feature.
- Supervised and managed other software developers and also worked as the lead backend developer.
- Worked with team members to gain further platform understandings and debugging.

#### Software Engineer - Wallets.Africa

Dec. 2017 - Apr. 2018

- Co-designed the database architecture and also built backend services that handle user managements and payment transactions.
- Integrated different payment gateways like Quickteller and Flutterwave on the platform to process payment.
- Implemented Barter Cards services to manage virtual dollar cards for consumers.
- Handled deployment of services on Microsoft azure machines.

# **Software Engineer -**SureBids Limited

Jan. 2015 - May 2017

2019

2022

2021

2016

2015

- Ensured the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of applications.
- Identified bottlenecks and bugs, and devised swift solutions to these problems.

M.Sc. Artificial Intelligence (Merit) - University of Lagos, Akoka, Nigeria

Serverless Framework Bootcamp: Node.js, AWS & Microservices, Udemy

Dynamic User Experience: Ajax Design and Usability, Interaction Design Foundation

Grade 5 Music Theory, Associated Board of the Royal Schools of Music, London (ABRSM)

NestJS Zero to Hero, Modern TypeScript Backend Development, Udemy

- Translated product documents and sprints into functional applications.
- Authored technical documentation to assist other developers in understanding the implemented application architecture and design methods.

#### **EDUCATION**

•	B.Sc. Systems Engineering (First Class) – University of Lagos, Akoka	2015
CE	RTIFICATIONS	
•	Docker and Kubernetes: The Complete Guide, Udemy	
•	React Front to Back 2022	2022
•	Software Architecture, University of Alberta through Coursera	2022
•	Data Structures & Algorithms, JavaScript, Udemy	2022

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

•	C#	•	ReactJS	•	PostgreSQL
•	ASP.NET CORE	•	Java	•	Git
•	ASP.NET MVC,	•	Python	•	AWS
•	JavaScript	•	HTML	•	Docker
•	NodeJS	•	CSS	•	CI/CD
•	NestJS	•	MSSQL	•	Serverless Framework
•	JQuery	•	MongoDB		

#### **PORTFOLIO**

- Settl.me (<a href="https://settl.me/">https://settl.me/</a>) is a platform that provides financial services for people within community at affordable rates.
- CerviTech (<a href="https://www.cervitech.com.ng/">https://www.cervitech.com.ng/</a>) is a mobile application that monitors neck posture with smart phones.
- SureGifts (<a href="https://suregifts.com/">https://suregifts.co.ke/</a>) is a platform for buying gift cards, egift cards & vouchers for birthdays, Christmas, valentine etc.
- SureGifts Business ( <a href="https://business.suregifts.com.ng/">https://business.suregifts.com.ng/</a>) A platform for corporate gift cards, rewards and loyalty for businesses.
- SureRemit ( <a href="https://sureremit.co/">https://sureremit.co/</a>) A platform for sending voucher, paying bills, mobile airtime top-up etc